# Miguel Rodrigues

Matosinhos, Porto, Portugal, 4460-170

🛮 (+351) 910 920 245 | 🗷 josemiguel443@gmail.com | 🛠 joserodrigues443.github.io | 🖸 JoseRodrigues443 | 🛅

josé-rodrigues-165290110 | **У** @JosRodr63795423

"A jack of all trades is a master of none, but oftentimes better than a master of one"



2020 - 2021

### Summary\_

With more than 6 years of experience as a Software Developer adept at bringing forth architecture design, testing, and maintenance of software systems. Created two teams from scratch (at Farfetch and Axonius) focused on guiding technical initiatives that allowed companies to invest in new areas of expertise.

## Work Experience \_\_\_

Axonius Inc.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER May 2022 - Current

- · Was the first member of the Portuguese tech cluster.
- Focused on growing tech knowledge for the new team.
- · Supported and created multiple adapters that allowed us to show security concerns and connections to the clients.
- Tech Stack: Python, Mongo, AWS.

Farfetch LC.

#### SENIOR RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

2021 - May. 2022

- The first member of the Research and Development team focused on investing in new tech solutions in areas like:
  - Virtual reality
  - Distributed computing (Blockchain and IPFS)
- · Was a node operator of the Diem Consortium Blockchain (formerly called Libra by Facebook/Meta) alongside elements from Spotify, Uber, Shopify, and many.
- Created a POC for virtual reality that allows clients to see 3D digital assets on the phone apps
- Used Nvidia Geforce Now API and Google Stadia
- · Started the Product Verity initiative project
  - Uses tags with random patterns to identify real luxury items. "Is this Gucci jacket really authentic? Let me take a photo of the unique
  - Then provides the real owner a unique digital certificate (an NFT on the blockchain) that identifies and validates the product.
  - The owner that way can resell or present their personal collection on a safe manner on the market
- Tech Stack: Dotnet, Typescript, Solidity (Ethereum blockchain programming language), Rust, Kafka, MSSQL, Cassandra, Docker, ArgoCD, Azure, OpenAPi, and Kubernetes.

Farfetch LC.

• Architectural role in the arch cluster at Farfetch

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Created and managed multiple company-critical projects like:
  - The Globalization project that allows micro-services to handle multi-country requirements (location, time-zones, best delivery paths, and other metrics)
  - The Communication Hub, a highway for internal communications of all the micro-services based on Kafka, used in internal communications and external contact to clients via SMS/Email/Webhooks/Integration's and others
- Beta team for the new deployment system using Elm Chart and ArgoCd
- Tech Stack: Dotnet, Python, Kafka, MSSQL, Cassandra, Docker, Azure, ArgoCD, OpenAPi and Kubernetes.

**Critical Manufacturing** SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2018 - 2019

· Core team developer for the manufacturing execution system (MES) that manages complex production pipelines

- The product development team creates and manages the main framework for developing a highly flexible MES that adapts to different clients like:
  - Renault, BMW, IKEA, Braun, Philips, Johnson & Johnson, and many others
- · Worked on the Migration Task Force responsible for migrating the legacy system, for a more robust and modern alternative
- Tech Stack: Dotnet, Angular, Typescript, MSSQL, Docker, Docker Swarm (moved to K8s) and Kubernetes.

E-Goi Matosinhos, Portugal

2017 - 2018 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- · Developed and maintained of the E-Goi Marketing system.
- Provided mechanisms to allow communication using Push notification, SMS, Email, voice marketing, and many others.
- **Tech Stack:** Laravel, Postgres, Redis, Vue, Linux.

E-Goi

JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Created the Sync2E-goi project that: Allows clients to integrate platforms to the E-goi marketing.
- Allowed Costumers to leave competitors like Mailchimp and migrate to the company Uses external systems like Zappier to improve the current E-Goi platform with minimal configuration
- Tech Stack: Laravel, Postgres, Redis, Vue, Linux.

#### Education

#### **ISEP (Higher Institute of Engineering of Porto)**

2016 - 2017

**B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING** 

2015 - 2018

#### **ATEC Training Academy**

2015 - 2018

SPECIALIST IN NETWORK AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS MANAGEMENT

- · Cisco network specialist CCNA 1
- · Cisco network specialist CCNA 2
- Cisco network specialist CCENT

# **Projects**

#### A Simple Blockchain in Go

JoseRodrigues443/gochain

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT GOCHAIN

- A Blockchain that supports both POW (proof of work) and POS (proof of stake) algorithms.
- See at: https://github.com/JoseRodrigues443/gochain

#### How make your content last forever on the web

JoseRodrigues443/blogger-ipfs

**BLOGGER IPFS** 

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

- A blog maker that uses the InterPlanetary File System protocol to create blog posts that cannot be lost and will scale to the entire world automatically
- See at: https://github.com/JoseRodrigues443/blogger-ipfs

#### How make your content last forever on the web

PUPPY SENDER TELEGRAM

SEE MORE PROJECTS AT MY BLOG

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

- · A blog maker that uses the InterPlanetary File System protocol to create blog posts that cannot be lost and will scale to the entire world automatically
- See at: https://github.com/JoseRodrigues443/puppy-sender-telegram

#### Blog posts, projects and many more to see

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

• See at: https://joserodrigues443.github.io

# **Extracurricular Activity**

#### B10S (B1t 0n the Security, Underground hacker team)

S.Korea

CORE MEMBER

Nov. 2011 - PRESENT

- · Gained expertise in penetration testing areas, especially targeted on web application and software.
- Participated on a lot of hacking competition and won a good award.
- Held several hacking competitions non-profit, just for fun.

#### WiseGuys (Hacking & Security research group)

MEMBER

Jun. 2012 - PRESENT

- · Gained expertise in hardware hacking areas from penetration testing on several devices including wireless router, smartphone, CCTV and set-
- Trained wannabe hacker about hacking technique from basic to advanced and ethics for white hackers by hosting annual Hacking Camp.

#### PoApper (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2017

Core Member & President at 2013

• Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.

• Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

#### PLUS (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- · Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.

#### MSSA (Management Strategy Club of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MEMBER

MEMBER

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017

- Gained knowledge about several business field like Management, Strategy, Financial and marketing from group study.
- · Gained expertise in business strategy areas and inisght for various industry from weekly industry analysis session.